<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HealthBook</string>
    <string name="title_activity_male">male</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="title_activity_login">Sign in</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome !"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigate">navigate</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>


    <string name="dietary_guidelines">
        1. Avoid being overweight. Have balanced, healthy diet rather than “Special
        diabetic foods”


        \n\n2. Daily energy intake must be estimated after considering such factors as
        age, sex, actual weight in relation to desirable weight, activity and
        occupation.

        \n\n3. Eat small meals (5-6 meals) every 2-3 hours rather than a large three
        meals a day to keep the energy levels high

        \n\n4. Include carbohydrates from foods high in fibre e.g. whole grains
        (unpolished cereals and millets), whole pulses and legumes like grams,
        soy, peas, beans, etc.

        \n\n5. Proteins should provide 12-15 % of the total energy intake for people with
        diabetes. Proteins from vegetable sources like pulses, soy, grams, peas,
        low fat milk, low fat curds, fish and lean meats are recommended

        \n\n6. It is advised to consume less than 10% of calories from saturated fat and
        less than 300mg of cholesterol/day.

        \n\n7. A mixture of oil is preferred than single oil. Poly unsaturated fatty acids
        and monounsaturated fatty acids containing vegetable oils (sunflower oil,
        groundnut oil, corn oil, gingelly oil) are preferred than hydrogenated fat
        (ghee, butter, etc.)

        \n\n8. Limit salt and salted foods. Sodium intake should not be no more than 6gm
        daily. Diabetics are susceptible to high blood pressure. For persons with
        hypertension and diabetes, the intake should be reduced to less than 3 g/
        day.

        \n\n9. Drink plenty of water and exercise regularly. Exercise increases sensitivity
        to insulin and helps to improve blood-sugar control.

        \n\n10. Avoid junk foods, aerated drinks and stick to natural drinks like fresh juice
        and water.

        \n\n11. Avoid ‘fasting’ and ‘feasting’.
    </string>

    <string name="probal_git"><a href="https://Github.com/Master-COLLiDER">Probal D. Saikia :\n Github.com/Master-COLLiDER</a></string>
    <string name="pranab_git"><a href="https://Github.com/prnbbora4">Pranab Bora:\n Github.com/prnbbora4</a></string>


</resources>
